# Karishma Saini

7 Huron Rd, Yonkers, NY, 10710, USA • ksaini7595@gmail.com • 914-433-7691 • linkedin.com/in/karishma-saini

karishmasaini.netlify.com

### **PROFILE**

Frontend Developer and UX Designer with a passion for web application development and success in creating user interactive prototypes. Experienced in technical writing, building user stories, and developing responsive web pages. Dedicate to provide innovative methods with the ability to follow technological trends and to achieve the organization's goal.



#### Front-End

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Semantic UI, Material UI Bootstrap 4, Tachyons

## **Content Management Systems**

Drupal, Wix, Shopify, Wordpress

#### Microsoft Suite

Word, PowerPoint, OutLook, Visio, Excel, OneDrive

#### **Back-End**

SQL, PHP, Mongo DB, Node, Express

#### **Software Tools**

inVision Studio, Chrome Developer Tools, Visual Studio Code Editor, Sublime Editor, NPM (Node Package Manager) Tool, Adobe Captivate

#### **Version Control**

Git, GitHub, BitBucket, SourceTree

#### **UX Designer**

Wireframes, Interactive Design, User Stories, Task Flows, User Research

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Financial Information Systems, Pace University, Graduate Assistant

Constructed, updated, and maintained user guides, training and SOPs (Standard Operating Procedure) documentation for company's operating systems, software, and tools.

- Monitored all web content, fixed technical errors, ensured smooth functioning of Pace University website with HTML and CSS under Drupal CMS.
- Provided technical expertise and updates in code reviews and application discussions.
- Assisted in development and maintenance of an API for integration with PHP and SQL.
- Knowledge of remote desktop connections, peer to peer file sharing and other applications associated with remote IT assistance.
- Responsible for handling clients' requests using the help desk ticketing system and phone calls

## Information Technology Support, Pace University, ITS Desk Assistant

• Provide technical support for 10-12 students, faculty or staff.

• Evaluate equipment in order to access technical issues such as connection with the WiFi or/and printers.

## kHinky.com, Web Developer Intern

• Responsible for developing a website using the content management system to showcase the company's products to increase sales.

- Created additional pages for the website to enhance visitors' experiences.
- Created image links and ensures that links are up to date; updates information on the pages so that content is
- Used Content Management Systems, Wix and Shopify platform to provide responsive webpages for customers.

### **GenCyber,** Computer Lab Intern

Set up and supported a learning lab for the Raspberry Pi for teachers to use for their labs.

- These labs encouraged teachers to use Raspberry Pi for their academic curriculum.
- Constructed, updated and maintained documentation to assist teachers to understand the functions of the Raspberry Pi

Jun 2016 - Jul 2016

May 2018 - May 2020

Sep 2015 - May 2018

May 2017 - Jul 2017

Bronx, USA

Valhalla, USA

Pleasantvilla, USA

#### PROJECTS

#### JV Automation Sep 2018 - May 2020

- Develop and implement Admin pages for the Journal Voucher web application using PHP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Webpages allow admin users to add and to remove roles for JV users.
- Admin has the ability to upload Excel files which contains the user's access to specific index(s) in the system.
- Work with Relational Databases such as MySQL, Oracle and SQL Server

- Developed and implemented an iOS application for nursing students to handle stress during exams.
- The application provides video demos for deep breathing exercises for users to reduce any stress or anxiety.
- Created users stories to demonstrate user's role for the application.
- Developed documentation, and flow charts to display the user interaction with the application.
- Maintaining Scrum discipline, focus & delivering tasks in a timely manner as per Sprint plans

## **EDUCATION**

Pace University, Seidenberg School of Computer Science and Information Systems,

Pace University, Seidenberg School of Computer Science and Information Systems,

2018 - 2020

Sep 2017 - Jan 2018

2014 - 2018

1/1

Master of Science (MS) in Information Technology | Concentration: Cybersecurity

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Pleasantville, USA